Kelsey Halloran

201 Osage Lane Pittsburgh, Pa 15208 ~ (908)328-3888 ~ kelseyhalloran92@gmail.com

PROFILE

Committed speech-language pathology clinician, with professional field experience, seeking a rewarding position as a Speech-Language Pathologist with a focus in pediatric/school aged population. Competent across a variety of settings and multicultural opportunities. Able to write appropriate goal individualized per client. Clear and concise professional writer. Familiar with the aspects of screening, evaluating and treating across age ranges and disoder types. Eager to use the knowledge gained through two years of clinical experience and completion of a Master's program in Speech-Language Pathology.

EDUCATION

Masters of Science in Speech-Language Pathology

August, 2016

East Stroudsburg University of Pennsylvannia - CAA Accredited

Cumulative GPA: 3.84

Bachelors of Science in Communication, Sciences and Disorders

May, 2014

The Pennsylvania State University

Minor: Psychology

Speech Language Pathology Praxis: Passed Pennyslvannia Teachers Certification (pending)

April, 2016 August, 2016

MOST RECENT PREVIOUS JOB EMPLOYMENT

Kelly Educational Staffing, Pittsburgh PA

September 2016 – Present

 Follow and execute lesson plans for grades kindergarten through 12th grade general education, physical education and special education classes

Extended School Year Speech-Language Pathologist for Bound Brook School District, Bound Brook NJ

June 2016 - August 2016

- Formally and informally conducted speech and language evaluation for pediatric and school aged students
- Develop IEP benchmark and long term goals
- Conducted therapy based on existing IEP goals for pediatric and school aged students, in the ABA classroom, with various speech, language and pragmatic disorders
- Use of both high and low tech assistive technology during therapy sessions

CLINICAL EXPERIENCE

Oxford Central School
Clinical Externship, Graduate Student Clinician

March 2016 – June 2016

- Conducted formal evaluation while administering the following standardized tests: Clinical Evaluation of Language Fundamentals, Fifth Edition (CELF-5), Stuttering Severity Instrument, Fourth Edition (SSI-4), Goldman Fristoe Test of Articulation, Second Editions (GFTA-2), Test of Auditory Processing Skills, Thrid Edition (TAPS-3)
- Performed screenings, evaluations and treatment on populations such as autism, down syndrome, selective mutism, auditory
 processing, ADD/ADHD, apraxia, receptive and expressive lagrauge delays and phonological delays
- Develop IEP benchmark and long term goals
- Provided theraputic techniques and activities to target phonological awareness, phonemic awareness, sound mastery, vocabulary, grammar, fluency, social skills, oral motor skills, feeding skills, expressive and receptive language
- Collaborated with teachers and child study team to develop Individualized Education Plans
- Planned and executed cotreats with occupational therapy
- Use of both high and low tech assistive technology during therapy sessions
- Implimentation of Response to Intervention (RTI) through 5-Minute Kids program

Hackettstown Medical Center

January 2016 - March 2016

Clincal Externship, Graduate Student Clinician

- Formally/informally conducted speech, language, cognitive, bedside swallow and modified barium swallow evaluations
- Wrote appropriate long term and short term goals
- · Conducted therapy for pediatric, school aged and adult clients with various speech, language, cognitive and swallowing disorders
- Administered the following standardized tests: Goldman Fristoe Test of Articulation Third Edition (GFTA-3), Bedside Evaluation
 Screening Test Second Edition (BEST-2), Preschool Language Scales, Fifth Edition (PLS-5), The Mini Mental State Examination
 (MMSE), Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA), Receptive-Expressive Emergent Language Test Thrid Edition (REEL-3)

East Stroudsburg University Speech and Hearing Clinic

Advanced Clinical Practicum, Graduate Student Clinician

- Formally and informally conducted speech and language evaluations for pediatric, school aged and adult clients
- Conducted hearing screenings using ASHA protocol and made appropriate referrals based on outcomes
- Determined appropriateness of current goals and created new goals based on evaluation outcomes
- Organized and planned activities to target short term and long term goals
- Employed a variety of materials to explore and manipulate target skills
- Administered the following standardized tests: Goldman Fristoe Test of Articulation, Second Edition (GFTA-2), Kahn-Lewis Phonological Analysis, Clinical Evaluation of Language Fundamentals Preschool-2 (CELF-Preschool-2), Aphasia Diagnostic Profiles (ADP), Pre-Reading Inventory of Phonological Awareness (PIPA), Boston Diagnostic Aphasia Examination (BDAE)

Head Start Fall 2014 - Fall 2015

Preschool speech and hearing screening

- Administered speech, language and hearing screeners to at risk preschoolers
- Made appropriate referrals based on screening outcomes

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

East Stroudsburg University of Pennsylvania

Summer 2015

May, 2016

Aphasia Group

- Held weekly group therapy sessions for individuals with various types of aphasia
- Collaborated with additional clinicians to deliver most appropriate intervention to support and increase communication skills

Pennsylvania State University

Fall 2010 - Spring 2012

January, 2015 - December 2015

Varsity Softball Team – Berks Campus

CERTIFICATIONS/PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

WCSLHA - Managing Complex Cases in Fluency/Stuttering

Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act, certified Fall, 2015 Spring, 2015

Passy Muir Training

CPR certified Fall, 2014

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT/VOLUNTEER SERVICES

Girls On The Run, volunteer March 2016 - June 2016

Special Olympics New Jersey Young Athletes, volunteer April 2016- May 2016

PREVIOUS JOB EMPLOYMENTS

Beaver Brook Country Club, Annandale NJ

May 2010 - August 2016

January 2016 – June 2016

Waitress, bartender, banquet server **Personal Tutor**

• For two 5th grade students in math

Substitute Teacher for Oxford Township School District, Oxford NJ

November 2012 - January 2016

Followed and executed lesson plans for grades kindergarten through 8th grade general education and physical education classes

Substitute Teacher Warren Hills School District, Washington NJ

November 2012- June 2015

Followed and executed lesson plans for freshman through senior general education and special education classes

Irvings Bagels, State College Pa

Crew shift leader – manager of the store on the weekends

August 2012 - May 2014

REFERENCES:

- Dr. Joseph Petrosino, Director of Special Services for Bound Brook School District
 - o jpetrosino@bbrook.org or 732-652-7989
- Amanda Ellis, M.S. CCC-SLP, Medical Externship Supervisor
 - Amanda.ellis@atlantichealth.org or 908-850-6835
- Rachel Chiara, M.S. CCC-SLP, School Based Externship Supervisor
 - o rchiara@oxfordcentral.org or 908-235-2987
- Katherine Lazzara, M.S. CCC-SLP ESU Clinic Supervisor/Instructor
 - o klazzara@po-box.esu.edu or 610-554-7006

LETTERS OF RECOMMENDATION UPON REQUEST